# 大煮干丝 丝丝相连
Da Zhu Gan Si
(Shredded dried tofu in chicken broth)
# 过年好
Happy New year!
# 你看下面坐的全是我们的小饭骨
I see many "Xiao Fan Gu" sitting there
# 是吧
Right
# 看我们老哥三在一块
Watching the three of us up here
# 向大家表演一个菜啊
Cooking this dish for you
# 二伯上场不动手
Er Bai is here, but not to cook.
# 背上一靠是吧
He just stands there with hands in the back.
# 三叔上场呢 把手搁前面
But San Shu is here wrapping his hands in front.
# 今天大爷不能这么做
Da Ye is not like them
# 还得亲力亲为 做一个老菜
I have to cook by myself. To prepare a traditional dish.
# 大煮干丝
Da Zhu Gan Si (shredded dried tofu in chicken broth)
# 这个吉庆的名字叫什么 丝丝相连
And there's a nicer name, Si Si Xiang Lian (Connected Tofu Threads)
# 为什么要叫丝丝相连 因为这四个丝儿菜
Why? Because it is finely shredded
# 那我们拿个藕不行吗
Why don't we use lotus roots?
# 拿藕不行 藕断了
No that's not going to work.
# 藕断丝连 这个是丝丝相连
The lotus has to break first to see the connective threads.
# 连着谁 连着媳妇
Connect with who? The loved ones?
# 连着大家的心 连着网友的心 连着朋友的心
To the hearts of friends, and our subscribers.
# 连着家人的心
Our families.
# 您说着三心就二意啊 三心二意
That's a lot of hearts. A lot of hearts to move in between.
# 您这就开始了 我来 三叔
Here we go, I got this San Shu
# 成了 来看大爷怎么煮
Let's learn from Da Ye
# 你现在发现没有 大爷一上来就非常兴奋
Did you notice how excited Da Ye is when he is up here?
# 他就把咱们俩人批评一顿
He first criticized the two of us (for not helping)
# 他自己亲力亲为干活
He is the one that's actually cooking
# 我是这么想的 他批评呢也是赞美
Well I think that's both criticism and compliment.
# 不是赞美
(No I don't think so)
# 为什么呢 因为别人他不批评 他只批评自己人
Why? He criticizes us because he care about us, because we are close to him.
# 杀熟呗 杀熟
Only the close ones.
# 烧点水
Get the water to boil first.
# 这干丝呢 我们选择的是扬州的豆干
We use the dried tofu from Yangzhou
# 这豆丝呢 需要一个刀功 上片
It requires a special technique to slice it like this.
# 上片
Into thing slices
# 大爷 您这叫什么刀法啊
What's the technique called?
# 片干丝一定要用片刀
We need a slicer to slice it
# 这个刀稍微厚点
The knife is a bit too thick.
# 片成薄片
Slice it into thin pieces.
# 丝丝相连
And chop it into thin threads.
# 然后呢大爷今天做了两件事
Da Ye did two things today.
# 第一是亲力亲为
First, he is cooking personally.
# 第二是煽情是丝丝相连
Second, he gave quite an emotional story to the dish.
# 切完了
OK that's done.
# 水开了 刚开了
Water is boiling
# 这个我们切好的干丝呢
Now the tofu
# 要用开水
Needs to go through the boiling water.
# 反复的烫两遍
Twice
# 水开了 水少不少
That's enough of boiling water.
# 不少
Just enough.
# 烫水的过程起什么作用呢
What's the purpose of it?
# 去掉黄泔水的味道
To remove the strange smell in tofu.
# 这个还需要切点笋丝
We also need some bamboo shoot.
# 这小刀法 盖了帽了
Look at the skills! Amazing!
# 大爷这叫宝刀不老啊 大爷课真不老啊
Da Ye is old but he still got it. (He's not that old anyway)
# 这个还要准备一盆
Now we need a bowl
# 刚才谁说宝刀不老啊 说对了一半
Yo were only half right about Da Ye
# 宝刀不老但是岁月催人老
He is aging, but his skills are still fresh.
# 你看到没有 大爷利用自己的余生 来传播中华美食文化
And he is trying his best to spread the knowledge on Chinese food culture.
# 传播技能 还有一个事儿
To demonstrate the cooking skills.(One more thing)
# 为什么要选择这个大煮干丝啊 为什么呀 这里面有故事
Why are we cooking this dish today? There's a story to it.
# 2017年 在北京召开了一次 一带一路的一个峰会
There was a Belt & Road Summit in Beijing in 2017.
# 在这个国宴上啊
At the state banquet
# 我们就有大煮干丝这道菜
We served this dish.
# 二倒水
Now the second time
# 还得放水
Enough?
# 不放了
Enough.
# 不烫笋丝吗 笋丝已经烫过了
Do you need to cook the bamboo shoot too?(No I did it already)
# 笋是先煮的 一块儿搁里头了
I cooked it before slicing.
# 煮干丝有几个要领
There are some tips for this dish.
# 煮干丝怎么才能软烂呢
How to cook through?
# 入口即化
(So that it) melts in your mouth?
# 要有大油 离不开大油
You need lard.
# 也就是说要有动物油
Or, animal fat.
# 熬大油也有小技巧
There are tips too in rendering the fat.
# 不是直接煸
Don't cook it directly in the pan.
# 要搁点水 用水熬
Do it with a bit of water.
# 慢慢熬着 三叔 给帮忙看着点
Take your time, San Shu, keep an eye on it.
# 我这还得切点 还得切点料
I still have some chopping to do.
# 这个干丝里面还有什么辅料啊
What else is needed for the dish?
# 还有鸡丝
Shredded chicken
# 这个鸡肉要用熟肌肉
You need to cook it before slicing.
# 鸡胸脯吗 鸡腿鸡胸都可以
Both chicken breast or thigh are fine.
# 大爷今天是玩了命了
Da Ye is serious today.
# 得玩点儿命
Yeah I am.
# 来点金华火腿
Some Jinhua Ham
# 这个煮干丝呢离不开金华火腿
You can't cook this dish without the ham.
# 有交鸡火煮干丝
Sometimes this dish is also called "shredded tofu with chicken and ham."
# 有的叫虾火煮干丝
Sometimes we use shrimp instead of chicken
# 鸡火干丝是以鸡丝为主 虾火干丝以虾仁为主
One focus on chicken, one on shrimps.
# 今天我把两样和成一块了
We have both of them today.
# 又有鸡又有虾
Chicken and shrimp.
# 2020年就是鸡和虾的一场恋爱
It's like a love story for chicken and shrimp in 2020.
# 好了 这个干丝这个料都准备好了
OK the preparation is completed.
# 淮扬菜管它叫什么呀
What's the local name of this ?
# 开阳 海米叫开阳
"Kaiyang" which is dried shrimps.
# 海米叫开阳 开门叫打烊
It's basically sun dried shrimps.
# 这个汤啊
About the broth.
# 是按照我们老饭骨原来的方法 用高压锅
We prepared it with a pressure cooker, according to our own recipe.
# 虾仁 先烫一下 用水把这个虾仁先烫一下
Shortly boil the shrimps
# 这个准备工作很重要
Preparation is crucial for this dish.
# 现在这个虾仁不用上浆
We don't need to marinate the shrimps nowadays.
# 因为它都是有保鲜剂 很脆的 能吃吗 能吃
It's kept fresh and good enough to cook directly.
# 我们给烫熟就行了
Just get it cooked.
# 现在所有的活都准备好了 开始操作了
OK we are all set and we can start cooking.
# 这个关键时刻来了
Critical moment!
# 高潮来了
It's all come down to here.
# 呛个锅
Ginger and spring onion in.
# 拿葱油呛个锅
To get the flavor out.
# 吃这个葱香味
The flavor of spring onion.
# 别炝大锅了 炝大锅这个葱就糊了
Make sure you don't burn it.
# 放汤
Now the broth in.
# 放这个吊好的浓鸡汤
Slow-cooked rich chicken broth.
# 鸡汤用高压锅压35分钟
The broth was cooked for 35 minutes in a pressure cooker.
# 再用大火冲个10分钟到20分钟就成白汤了
Then, boiled for 10-20 minutes on high heat until the color turned white.
# 这个时候我们要下料了
We can put the ingredients in now.
# 先下海米
First, the dried shrimps.
# 开阳
aka. "Kaiyang"
# 熟鸡丝
Cooked chicken meat.
# 都搁里边吧 人多啊
All of it, we have many to feed today.
# 大爷 小饭骨问老饭骨一个问题啊
(We've got a question here.)
# 这个菜的制作要点都有什么
(What are the most important steps?)
# 第一个要点 要烫干丝
First, pass the shredded tofu through boiling water.
# 两遍 烫两遍
Twice, to remove unwanted flavor.
# 去掉豆干的这个黄泔水的味道 也就是豆腥味
The slightly strange smell from soybeans.
# 煮的时候不着急放调味
Do not season it too early.
# 因为早放调味这个干丝煮不烂的
It takes time to cook through.
# 你看这汤很白 但白的给你感觉颜色不是很好看
The broth is white, but it doesn't look very nice.
# 我往里面加点老抽
Let me put a little bit of "Lao Chou"(dark soy sauce).
# 够了
Enough
# 它颜色变成了这种黄
Now it turns into a yellow color.
# 这黄看的舒服了
Looks much better
# 给我来点盐 来点糖 来点胡椒
Salt, sugar and pepper.
# 胡椒少不了
Don't forget about pepper.
# 盐不够
A bit more salt.
# 你看这颜色就非常漂亮了
Now that's a beautiful color.
# 看出来了吧我们这老哥三这感觉
See how smooth our collaboration is?
# 你看煮到这种程度呢
When it's cooked to this point
# 我们要放点大油
we put some lard in.
# 这大油要分三次放
We need to do that for three times.
# 一次要放一调羹
One spoon each.
# 大爷不是做麻婆豆腐啊
(Are we cooking Mapo Tofu today?)
# 三次勾芡
(Which needs to pour the starch in three times)
# 我们这里还有豆尖 这个刚才没向大家介绍
We also have pea sprouts tip here, which I forgot to mention.
# 这豆尖是小豆苗的豆尖
These are very young sprouts.
# 这个汤可真棒啊
We've got a really nice broth today.
# 这个豆尖 是从这上面取下来的
We used the young tips of these sprouts.
# 这是小豌豆尖
Sprouts of pea.
# 这个豆尖很嫩也很香
They are tender and fragrant.
# 二次加油
Second spoon of lard.
# 这时候我们把火腿放进去
Now, ham can go in.
# 因为这火腿 放早了也不行放完了也不行
We have to get the timing right for the ham.
# 太早了就烂了
The ham gets overcooked if we put it in to early.
# 火腿味煮没了 不香了
And it loses all of its aroma..
# 煮干丝大油一定要跟上 三次 第三次了
Now it's time for the third spoon of lard.
# 大火煮
Cook it on high heat.
# 有这大油你就能吧这汤泛白
You need the lard to achieve the white color of the broth.
# 现在开始尝味
Let's have a taste.
# 你看这个汤
Look at the broth.
# 比这个汤 还要显得浓
It gets even thicker.
# 这是大油起的作用
Thanks to the lard.
# 下面把虾仁放进去
OK now the shrimps.
# 够了
Enough
# 豆苗顺着锅边
Put the sprouts in alone the edge.
# 这个菜为什么放豆尖啊
Why don't we use pea for it?
# 好看啊 好看你还不放味精
Because the sprouts look better. And we don't need MSG for this.
# 这个比味精鲜 对 它就是味精
The sprouts bring enough umami to it.
# 好 OK 大爷齐活了
OK we are done!.
# 齐活了 找一个大碗啊
Let's get a large bowl.
# 大煮干丝 丝丝相连
Da Zhu Gan Si
(Shredded dried tofu in chicken broth)
# 今天按照以往啊有一个巅峰的感受啊
I feel different today. Usually I am the judge.
# 原来都是老饭骨审小饭骨 给评小饭骨
I'm used to judge you, but not today.
# 今天倒了一个个儿
Today it's the other way around.
# 小饭骨评老饭骨
The "Xiao Fan Gu" are judging the "Lao Fan Gu".
# 我们向你们学习
We are here to learn.
# 今天你们不用客气啊 你们看见了没有啊
Don't be shy.
# 来 过来尝尝
Have a taste.
# 二伯 受不起
What an honor for me.
# 鲜香甜样样行
Umami, aroma, sweetness, it has all of it.
# 好
Really nice.
# 丝丝相连 虾仁脆弹 这个汤是真鲜啊
Tofu is nicely sliced, shrimps are tender and firm. And what an amazing broth.
# 这是2017年一带一路的国宴用菜
This is a dish from our state banquet in 2017.
# 上面还有一个特殊的配头
We need something special to go with it.
# 好酒配好菜
A nice baijiu (liquor).
# 小饭骨敬老饭骨一杯
Here is to the "Lao Fan Gu", from us "Xiao Fan Gu".
# 丝丝相连
Stay connected
# 春节快乐
Happy Chinese New Year
# 我是大爷
I am Da Ye
# 我是二伯
I am Er Bai
# 我是三叔
I am San Shu
# 我们是 老饭骨
We are Lao Fan Gu
# 欢迎大家订阅我们老饭骨YouTube频道
Please subscribe to our YouTube Channel
# 我们老饭骨组合就是教大家做菜
We are here to teach you how to cook.
# 传授一些精湛的小厨艺 希望大家喜欢
And to share with you some little tips. Hope you like them.
# 希望全球的美食爱好者喜欢我们
We that hope everyone around the world likes our videos.
# 订阅我们的频道 点亮我们的小铃铛
Subscribe to our channel, and click the notification bell.
# 同时 在这里我们祝全球华人
Here, we wish everyone
# 万事如意 恭喜发财
A lot of happiness and fortune in the coming new year!